### Contact

+61421589160 (Mobile) shedha.anshita@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/anshi1 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Content Management Systems (CMS)

Editorial

**Content Strategy** 

### Languages

English (Full Professional)

#### Certifications

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Google Analytics for Beginners Medicines Australia Code of Conduct Learn SQL Course Social Media Analytics with R

# **Anshita Shedha**

Driving growth through strategic content and storytelling. Sydney, New South Wales, Australia

## Summary

As a child, I loved stories—telling them, hearing them, and creating them. As an adult and a professional content creator and communication specialist, this fascination with stories has evolved into crafting compelling narratives for people, companies, brands, and ideas. Several companies have joined me on my quest to express themselves creatively, whether it is a Big Four bank venturing into the lifestyle magazine and TV space, a serious consulting business debuting on Instagram and finding that it makes their consultants more relatable, or a top pharmaceutical company succeeding in holding a doctor's attention a little longer to potentially save lives.

Will you be the next to join me on this creative journey?

## Experience

Commonwealth Bank
Digital Content Manager
November 2023 - Present (9 months)
Sydney, New South Wales, Australia

I am on this journey with CommBank until November 2024, when my contract ends. CommBank expanded into the lifestyle magazine space with \*The Brighter Side\* (also a TV show on 10 and 10 Play) and chose me to be the editorial lead behind its web content. The show is available to stream on 10 Play and you can read the content on the website here [https://www.commbank.com.au/brighter.html].

The results have been astounding. Within three months, we have noticed a 166% increase in traffic, with the audience often spending nearly a minute on the page. Who knew that in this blink-and-miss swiping era, people would still enjoy reading a recipe?

AstraZeneca

Content Strategist

September 2021 - May 2023 (1 year 9 months)

Australia

A digital laggard in the wake of a global pandemic, AstraZeneca found itself struggling. Most of its content was on paper, lying on the floor of copy rooms, in bulky PDFs that no one could slice, or sitting in obscure Vimeo channels as hour-long videos. Enter me, as a digital content strategist. I used a three-step approach to my content strategy at AstraZeneca. First, I commissioned a company-wide content audit to understand our opportunities. Next, using the famous hub, hero, hygiene model of content popularized by YouTube, I helped AZ brands understand what's important for them. Last, using the COPE model (Create Once, Publish Everywhere), I helped brands create and reuse content that mattered on channels and in formats where it would be most effective.

Minor enhancements like chapterizing long videos, adding subtitles, and creating accessible content added to the brand's trustworthiness. The brand awareness grew from 22% to 48%. But more than that, doctors were now aware of lifesaving, better medicines and therapies.

It's good to know that I made a difference.

Infosys Consulting
1 year 6 months

Global Communications Manager August 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 6 months)

Sydney, New South Wales, Australia

Marketing Communications Manager September 2019 - January 2020 (5 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

Despite a wealth of knowledge on its content hub, Infosys was lacking some lustre.

When I joined as a Global Communications Manager, I was tasked with creating long-form content assets (such as CEO whitepapers) and promotional "packs" across various channels—LinkedIn, internal platforms, and blogs. I thought, "Just because the content is well-researched, almost academic and serious, doesn't mean we can't have some fun with it."

My strategy involved making content digestible and relatable while exploring new channels and formats. I worked on 1-page PDFs and image infographics

that would use key figures from the whitepapers for our socials. Video was an underutilised tool in our arsenal, and I used precursors of Sora, like Lumen5, to create short and snappy LinkedIn videos to introduce our long-form blogs on a £0 budget. For internal comms, I convinced the company to make a debut on Instagram, with the key strategy of making junior consultants the stars of the show and redirecting newsletters to the new IG channel.

The results spoke for themselves. Within the first six months, employee engagement on internal communication platforms rose by 20%. The company's LinkedIn followers increased by an average of 16% year on year. The website traffic grew by 34%. We also generated 26 well-researched, high-quality whitepapers annually, each with a minimum of 500 downloads.

Tink Labs Limited
Social Media & Content Manager
September 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 1 month)
London, United Kingdom

Tink Labs, formerly known as "handy," was a Hong Kong-based tech company renowned for its innovative "handy" smartphone, which enhanced guest experiences in hotel rooms. As the Social Media and Content Manager, my challenge was to increase user engagement and brand awareness. We initiated the #WhyltsHandy challenge, partnering with hotels to promote it on their social media platforms. Guests were encouraged to share why the "handy" smartphone was useful or 'handy' during their stay, tagging @handy and using the hashtag #WhyltsHandy. This initiative resulted in building relationships with influencers in the travel and hospitality sectors, which were later leveraged to expand our brand reach. It also strengthened partnerships with hotels and generated valuable user-generated content showcasing real-life uses of the device at minimal cost. Guest submissions provided insights into how they perceived and utilised the device, helping us refine our marketing and product strategies. As a result, social media engagement increased by 33%, and website enquiries rose by 25%.

Ageas Federal Life Insurance Content Strategist September 2015 - July 2018 (2 years 11 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

The CEO of Ageas Federal (then known as IDBI Federal) had a vision - to promote life insurance positively and to be perceived as a partner in improving their customers' health. To achieve this, Ageas sponsored marathons across

India - Delhi, Mumbai, Kolkata, and Kochi. They partnered with Sachin Tendulkar to be a brand ambassador and had over 4,000 registrations for the first run. The stakes were high.

I was brought on as a Content Strategist to oversee the content created for the promotions of the marathons. Together with M&C Saatchi, I came up with the proposition of 'Keep moving', embodying the always-on culture of Mumbai. The integrated marketing communications campaign involved several YouTube videos and social content with sights and sounds of the city, along with motivating messages from Sachin. The videos garnered millions of views.

Within a year, we doubled the registrations, with the 3rd edition attracting almost 16,000 runners.

Larsen & Toubro
Digital Communications Officer
September 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 1 month)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

I was the Global Communication Officer, responsible for supporting multiple business units with their promotional communications, including industrial videos, pitch videos, brochures, thought leadership blogs, and more.

#### **BBDO** Worldwide

Copywriter

February 2012 - September 2013 (1 year 8 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Copywriter for Mercedes-Benz, Raymond, Pedigree and P&G.

# Point Blank Advertising Pvt Ltd

Executive

January 2011 - February 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Client servicing and copywriting for Cipla, Ranbaxy and Bausch & Lomb.

R K SWAMY BBDO Summer Intern

Summer milem

May 2010 - June 2010 (2 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

## Education

University of Greenwich

Social Media Analytics, Social Media Analytics using R · (2018)

University of Tasmania

Medicines Australia Code of Conduct, Pharmaceutical Marketing and Management  $\cdot$  (2021)

University of Mumbai

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Marketing · (2011)

University of Mumbai

Bachelor of Science - BS · (2008)